<archimate:Goal
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Data collected at granularity to reflect physical process being modelled"
    id="id-f23077e1-7549-4c82-9424-be6adbecfcd2"
    documentation="Data architecture and / or configuration is structured such that the granularity (i.e. the fineness of detail) and / or attribution (i.e. its descriptive fields or values) better reflect the corresponding physical processes on the ground, or better support current business objectives.&#xA;&#xA;When data is architected and / or configured to monitor and analyse certain physical processes, or to support certain business processes and outcomes, it satisfies the requirements in terms of the depth and breadth of detail at which corresponding data is captured or apportioned, and which corresponding data is conceptually linked to other related data.&#xA;&#xA;Frameworks, templates, standards, policies and procedures are developed to ensure that data architecture and configuration is accurate, common, and consistent.&#xA;&#xA;Where data architecture or configuration is constrained or imposed by line of business systems or processes, then current systems or processes are extended or supplemented so that data is reconfigured, regrouped, and realigned, to accurately reflect the corresponding physical process, or support its corresponding business objective.&#xA;&#xA;Physical and business processes are first appraised and understood in conceptual terms. They are defined, mapped out, and broken down into their conceptual business entities, essential attributes, and granular levels, according to a single, common enterprise view free from the restrictions and constraints imposed by current line of business system architecture.&#xA;Where data granularity is excessively detailed, it is rationalised and simplified in light of and in line with the business outcome it is designed to bring about.">
  <properties
      key="Cultural goal Classification"
      value="Data Architecture"/>
</archimate:Goal>
