<archimate:Principle
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Transformation"
    id="id-95dfe22f-86f0-4f9d-ac2c-b30ee336632b"
    documentation="Being brave enough to make big changes, starting with a blank sheet of paper, when we need to. Transforming the way we work with customers, partners and suppliers, focusing on outcomes, to continue being a successful business.&#xA;Love Every Drop is our shared vision for putting water at the heart of a whole new way of living. It is an audacious ambition; one that will require us to innovate and collaborate to transform our business and to change for the better.&#xA;Transformation is the third pillar of our culture.&#xA;Transformation is about being bold, keeping our eyes open to the world, thinking big, and being relentless in making those small changes that can make a big impact.&#xA;We want to transform the way we work with our partners and suppliers, focusing heavily on the ten outcomes we agreed with our customers.&#xA;Our leading customer service ethos, together with cutting-edge social marketing initiatives will help reshape how society values and uses water. And we’re well on the way to transforming how we work. For example:&#xA;We’re taking steps to adapt to and prepare for the challenges of a changing climate by reducing carbon use across our business. Through innovative new products, and collaboration between colleagues, partners, and suppliers we cut our operational carbon emissions by 9% of CO2e in 2013-14 from a 2010 baseline.&#xA;We generate our own power. In 2013-14, we generated 64GWh of renewable energy.&#xA;We reduced the embodied carbon used in building assets such as water mains, sewers, and pumping stations by 41% between 2010 and 2014.&#xA;By the end of 2014, our Keep it Clear campaign had reduced blockages in targeted hotspots by 49%.&#xA;We’re continuing our campaign to reduce leakage. It was at its second lowest ever level in 2014, with performance 9% better than our Ofwat target.&#xA;In AMP6, our capital investment will be delivered through four frameworks, with contractors signing up to collaborative agreements."/>
