<archimate:Principle
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Innovation"
    id="id-410d3f49-a90d-43de-9694-9fec2abc67b8"
    documentation="Setting ourselves, partners and suppliers tough goals to encourage step changes, being open to new ideas, and innovative thinking.&#xA;&#xA;Facing up to the tough challenges of the future, like climate change and population growth, means all of us need to find new and more efficient ways of working. By doing this we’ll achieve the goals we’ve set ourselves.&#xA;Love Every Drop is our strategy for helping us do this, so we can transform our business into a water company for the 21st century.&#xA;This is why one of the three pillars of our business culture is Innovation.&#xA;Anglian Water will become a hub of innovation in our region, creating wealth and jobs. We want our employees, partners, and suppliers to be open to new ideas, to think innovatively and to operate more sustainably. &#xA;We have developed programmes and channels to improve collaboration with internal and external colleagues, identify great ideas and test out how it could all work:&#xA;We have our core Innovation Programme, testing out new ideas and technology in all areas of the business.&#xA;Our Water Innovation Network (WIN) runs events and an idea submission process for supply chain companies to get new ideas into the heart of Anglian Water’s business.&#xA;We have Think Space, our internal crowd-sourcing system, to gather all the great ideas from colleagues across the business, review them in a consistent way and allow staff across the business to view them and get involved.&#xA;The ‘Shop Window’ is an area covering Newmarket where we are trialling a huge range of innovation and business improvement projects all together. It will showcase what the water industry of the future will look like.&#xA;We play a key role in the national Innovation Leadership Group, chaired by Defra. This group has developed a strategy to align UK research and innovation programmes with national priorities like energy, climate change and wealth creation.&#xA;We’ve already made real progress in instilling innovation into everyday business. Here are just some of the fantastic things that you’ve been up to: -&#xA;Our award winning in-house display unit, designed in collaboration with Green Energy Options, allows customers to see exactly how much water they’re using and to set a ‘water budget’.&#xA;Our new Hall Water Treatment Works near Lincoln uses an innovative way of treating water. We worked with UV technology supplier Trojan and GTM to develop a treatment process that uses UV light energy and hydrogen peroxide to successfully remove a pesticide called metaldehyde.&#xA;Our BeachAware system uses state of the art technology and data handling systems to allow us to provide beach owners, the Environment Agency and others with near real-time information on water quality in our coastal waters.&#xA;We have developed and patented a new way to condition sewage sludge prior to treatment called HpH (Heating, Pasteurisation, Hydrolysis). This process also generates 5% more methane gas, which we convert into electricity. This innovation has saved Anglian Water around £3 million in capital expenditure and the increases in gas production will lead to a further operational cost benefit of more than £400,000 a year."/>
