<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Metadata Management"
    id="id-7b00ad0a-1849-4141-9b63-b479733bea81"
    documentation="A managed metadata environment provides the capability to capture, centralise, structure, store, maintain, integrate, search, measure, distribute, deliver, query, report, analyse, and leverage metadata.&#xA;&#xA;Metadata is data about data. It describes its meaning, context, and value. Anywhere there is data, there is metadata (e.g. technical metadata, content metadata, business metadata, process metadata, governance metadata, requirements, definitions, specifications, models, designs, security, licenses, etc.).&#xA;&#xA;For example, the conditional logical criteria that define whether a mains burst is ‘reportable’ to OFWAT, is metadata. So is the Business Intelligence Competency Centre (BICC) technical specification for a data import and transformation mechanism. Even the column heading on a spreadsheet can be considered as metadata, as without them the data contained in the spreadsheet is meaningless.&#xA;&#xA;A managed metadata environment provides a centralised location in which to store and access metadata efficiently, so it can be found and accessed easily.&#xA;&#xA; A metadata management capability will enable Anglian Water to better:&#xA;•&#x9; Integrate, adapt, and re-use data.&#xA;•&#x9; Increase the value of strategic information to facilitate more effective decision-making.&#xA;•&#x9; Lower the impact of staff turnover by enforcing thorough documentation.&#xA;•&#x9; Reduce data-oriented research time through effective search mechanisms.&#xA;•&#x9; Bridge the gap between business users and IT, increasing confidence in data.&#xA;•&#x9; Increase the speed of system development.&#xA;•&#x9; Reduce risk of project failure during change management.&#xA;•&#x9; Identify and reduce the amount of redundant data and processes, etc.&#xA;&#xA;Metadata is everywhere, so it is vital to establish a strategy, scope, and architectural approach. There are many toolsets, standards, and methodologies (e.g. OMG, CWM, IMM, MDC, OIM, RDF, ISO11179) to evaluate and choose from, which will help guide the ongoing development of this capability. Subject areas should be incorporated in turn, as part of an ongoing, incremental, integration capability, planned and phased with the most cost effective areas given highest priority after due consideration of cost v benefit v risk."/>
