<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Data Security"
    id="id-e5434696-0b4e-43d3-8a5e-fbb0f1dbca76"
    documentation="A strategic Data Security capability will enable Anglian Water to develop and promote awareness of a comprehensive set of data security policies and standards, in line with overall business strategy, to provide a balanced and effective security function whereby the right people can use and update data in the right way and inappropriate access is restricted, without stifling innovation.&#xA;&#xA;A comprehensive set of policies, standards, and controls, is needed to further adapt to the changing nature of risk in the business, particularly with regards to the change in security perimeter that comes about with use of cloud-based applications.&#xA;&#xA;There is no one way of implementing data security to meet privacy and confidentiality requirements. Anglian Water should design its own security controls, which meet the requirements of its stakeholders, regulators, and the law, and implement them in line with industry standards (such as ISO 27000), to cover areas such as: Tools, Encryption methods, Transmission protocols, Documentation, Remote access, Coding standards, Breach procedures Mobile devices / portable storage (use and physical disposal) A balanced and effective security function ensures that the right people can use and update data in the right way, and that inappropriate access is restricted without stifling innovation.&#xA;&#xA;In terms of strategic data security, the policies and standards will be more granular than general IT security policies. In particular, an Identity Management capability will enable Anglian Water to define and manage permissions and privileges by role group hierarchies,&#xA;whereby data access is linked to business function rather than managed per user. Assignments are then made via group membership, and linked to Human Resources user processes. To avoid data integrity issues, centrally managed security matrices (data-to-process, data-to-role, groups, permissions, and privileges) will be used for planning and tracking.&#xA;&#xA;The capability should also enable Anglian Water to map and assess its security perimeter. Currently there are potentially more than 500 cloud systems in use, and the number is growing every day. Tools are needed to help monitor and track the outflow of sensitive data from the internal network.&#xA;All control systems will be treated as if they fell under the official criteria of the Centre for the Protection of National Infrastructure (CPNI), and in particular, security for all operational technology systems such as Telemetry (IRIS) will be compartmentalised.&#xA;&#xA;Data governance will increase awareness of these standards and procedures, and ensure that they are always specified and adhered to for every new data development project and initiative. The monitoring and rporting of authentication, access, and usage behaviourwill enable data stewards to detect unusual patterns."/>
