<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Data Retention and Archiving"
    id="id-93cb5362-3a01-4325-910e-fe33627101fb"
    documentation="During its operational lifetime, data may be extracted,transformed, imported, edited, updated, cleansed,converted, integrated, segregated, aggregated, backed up, recovered, archived, retrieved, and deleted. As such, data archiving is a fundamental feature of the operational data lifecycle management capability.&#xA;&#xA;Data archiving is a shared responsibility between data stewards and information asset owners. Although the physical process of archiving and retrieving data is largely an operational, technical activity, the data retention aspect is a planning and design activity owned by the business.&#xA;&#xA;A data archiving capability should be based on and supported by a consistent, standardised approach to data retention across all systems and subject areas, with policies setting out the general principles and timeframes accordingly. process, such that for every project, an agreement is&#xA;reached on how to manage the relevant data over its useful lifetime.&#xA;&#xA;The fundamental rule for all aspects of data management is that the cost of maintaining data should&#xA;not exceed its value to the organization. Not all data should reside forever in primary storage, as it will eventually incur a maintenance and performance cost.&#xA;&#xA;Data that is not actively needed to support business processes should be archived to some sort of secondary storage. Not all data should reside forever in primary storage, as it will eventually incur a maintenance and performance cost. The cost of maintaining data should not be allowed to exceed its value to the organisation.&#xA;&#xA;Data retention decisions are the responsibility of the data owners, and data governance needs to ensure that these decisions are made early on in the design&#xA;&#xA;Data that is obsolete should be purged in line with data security standards and policies, as it may be-&#xA;come a liability and a security risk if retained longer than necessary.&#xA;&#xA;The physical aspects of an archiving capability will require the design and creation of secondary storage areas, secondary database servers, database replication, table partitions, backups, and maintenance plans."/>
