<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Governance and Ownership"
    id="id-57c23e28-de0d-4899-a4a4-9c9adb4056d9"
    documentation="Effective data management depends on the creation and enforcement of policies (short statements of management intent and fundamental rules), standards (comprehensive, detailed, prescriptive guidelines), and procedures (steps, tasks), therefore it relies heavily on the data governance capability. Data governance is not the same thing as IT governance, it is focused exclusively on the management of data.&#xA;&#xA;Governance is the responsibility of data owners and stewards, who:&#xA;&#xA;•&#x9; Sponsor and oversee data management projects and services&#xA;•&#x9; Take an enterprise perspective to ensure enterprise wide integration and consistency&#xA;•&#x9; Represent enterprise and departmental interests&#xA;•&#x9; Provide input to data policies, standards, metrics, and procedures&#xA;•&#x9; Monitor and enforce data policies and practices&#xA;&#xA;Data governance and ownership is an enabler of all data management capabilities:&#xA;&#xA;•&#x9; Enterprise Data Architecture Modelling: The enterprise data model should be developed and maintained jointly by data architects and data owners working together in teams oriented by subject area. Data owners review, validate, approve, and refine new data requirements, and assist data architects in the integration of these requirements into the enterprise data architecture, paying particular attention to the alignment of the enterprise data model with key business strategies, processes, organizations, and systems.&#xA;•&#x9; Data Modelling &amp; Design: Data owners assist data architects to integrate data requirements into the logical models, physical data models, and database designs, participate in database testing and conversion, and ensure consistent use of terms.&#xA; •&#x9; Master Data Management: Data owners control the creation, update, and retirement of code values and other reference data, define master data management requirements, identify and help resolve master data management issues.&#xA;•&#x9; Metadata: Data owners create and maintain business metadata, define metadata access and integration needs, and use metadata to make effective data stewardship and governance decisions.&#xA;&#xA;Defining and maintaining business metadata is at the heart of data stewardship. &#xA;•&#x9; Data Security: Data owners own the data, therefore it is their responsibility to define security, privacy and confidentiality requirements, identify and resolve data security issues, assist in data security audits, and classify the confidentiality of information in documents and other information products.&#xA;•&#x9; Data Quality Assessment: Data owners define data quality requirements and business rules, test application edits and validations, assist in the analysis, certification, and auditing of data quality, lead data clean-up efforts, identify proactive ways to solve root causes of poor data quality, promote data quality awareness, and ensure data quality requirements are met. Data stewards actively profile and analyse data quality in partnership with data professionals. &#xA;•&#x9; Data Operations &amp; Support: Data owners define the requirements for data recovery, retention and performance, and help negotiate service levels in these areas. They help to identify, acquire, and control externally sourced data.&#xA;&#xA;Clear, unambiguous ownership of data subject areas by appointed subject matter experts ensures that data is managed consistently, by those who are accountable for it, in support of the overall business strategy."/>
