<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Data Modelling and Design"
    id="id-2a88afa6-5dd8-427e-a9d5-fdd0f0e7de25"
    documentation="Data Modelling and Design is the capability to analyse business data requirements, and to design, implement, deploy, and maintain the data structures which underpin analytical (business intelligence) and operational (application) solutions which meet those requirements. It is a fundamental part of the system development lifecycle and relies on the effective collaboration of data owners, data analysts, solution architects, and developers.&#xA;&#xA;Data modelling is an iterative process, at successive levels of appropriate detail:&#xA;&#xA;Conceptual data model:&#xA;•&#x9; A visual, high-level perspective on a subject area of importance to the business, containing only the critical business entities and relationships.&#xA;Logical data model:&#xA;•&#x9; A detailed, normalised representation of all data entities and attributes, usually in support of a specific usage context.&#xA;Physical data model:&#xA;•&#x9; An optimized implementation of detailed data requirements in light of technology constraints, application usage, performance requirements, and modelling standards.&#xA;&#xA;Data Modelling &amp; Design is the capability which forges the link between data capture and information consumption. It is a balance between satisfying short-term business needs and protecting long-term business interests by ensuring that data resides in structures that are integrated, adaptable, and reusable.&#xA;&#xA;Data Modelling and Design standards ensure a consistent architectural approach for the design of applications, operational data stores, data marts, metadata repositories, master data management, and data quality assessment environments, which is particularly crucial in the field of data warehousing, where well-managed data acquisition and transformation processes, and the conformity of dimensions, are the primary enablers of an interconnected analytical data model. Alignment with the Enterprise Data Architecture Model is key. Local data development must integrate with, and be incorporated into, the enterprise view."/>
