<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Data Quality Assessment"
    id="id-dc311362-9c4f-410a-a10a-a9146ae16546"
    documentation="Data quality scoring provides trust and confidence in data, and a scientific basis for issue resolution and improvement.&#xA;Data quality is synonymous with information quality, since poor data quality results in inaccurate information which has a material impact on business performance. A Data Quality Assessment capability will enable Anglian Water to analyse data in order to measure and quantify its conformity to data quality expectations, i.e. score the extent to which data is ‘fit for purpose’.&#xA;&#xA;Data Quality Assessment is an ongoing, incremental capability. Subject areas should be incorporated in turn, with the most cost effective areas given highest priority, after due consideration of cost v benefit v risk.&#xA;&#xA;In collaboration with subject matter experts, data quality expectations are formalised as programmatic rules concerning accuracy, completeness, consistency, integrity, timeliness, uniqueness, and validity. These business rules are based on parameters such as value presence and record completeness, value domain conformance, mapping conformance, range conformance, format compliance, and conformity of data definitions. By using defined data rules proactively to validate data, Anglian Water can distinguish those records that conform to defined data quality expectations and those that do not. In turn, these data rules are used to baseline the current level of data quality as compared to ongoing assessments.&#xA;&#xA;These rules form the basis of measurements and acceptability thresholds, developed with accountability, control, relevance, and stewardship in mind. Measurement will enable Anglian Water to report on the relationship between flawed data and missed business objectives. Measurements that do not meet the specified acceptability thresholds indicate non-conformance, and that some data remediation is necessary.&#xA;&#xA;When extended into Business As Usual activities, a data quality incident tracking capability enables the categorisation of data issues into incident hierarchies such that they can be classified, logged, and tracked according to data quality issue resolution service level agreements. Issue resolution activity can then be standardised, with associated data governance around assignment processes, escalation procedures, and resolution workflows. The creation of a closed feedback loop will ensure that issue resolution is not only about cleansing data downstream, but also addressing the root causes of data defects at source."/>
