<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Master Data Management"
    id="id-5b4d8087-bd21-4245-be03-38c2e7df9184"
    documentation="Master Data Management establishes centralised, authoritative, ‘golden’ datasets which are propagated out to satellite systems that equire such data. It is a key enabler of system and data integration.&#xA;&#xA;A Master Data Management capability will address the challenges that exist where different business units, processes, and systems share similar information for different purposes, but where purpose-specific requirements have led to purpose-specific applications and fragmentation of that data across systems.&#xA;&#xA;It will enable Anglian Water to manage how shared data is created, integrated, maintained, and used&#xA;throughout the enterprise, by establishing centralised, authoritative, ‘golden’ datasets which are propagated out to all the systems that require such data. A new data integration architecture will control shared access, replication, and flow of data in order to ensure data quality and consistency, either from a single system of record (where master data is consolidated into a single line of business system), or via a ‘hub-and-spoke’ architecture with a dedicated master data hub data store that serves as the single, central point of reference for all satellite operational and reporting applications.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;Business logic will be developed to match, merge, and link data from multiple sources, and to provide a certain degree of confidence for each match. &#xA;&#xA;For all shared data subject areas, the fundamental questions will need to be addressed:&#xA;•&#x9; What data is required for specific needs, and how do those needs overlap?&#xA;•&#x9; What data is describing the same person, place, or thing?&#xA;•&#x9; Where does that data originate, and how does each instance differ?&#xA;•&#x9; Which instance is of the highest quality?&#xA;•&#x9; How can inconsistencies be reconciled?&#xA;&#xA;Master Data Management is an ongoing, incremental, integration capability, planned and phased. Subject areas should be incorporated in turn, with the most cost effective areas given highest priority, after due consideration of cost v benefit v risk.&#xA;&#xA;A Master Data Management capability will address the challenges that exist where different business units, processes, and systems share similar information for different purposes, but where purpose-specific requirements have led to purpose-specific applications and fragmentation of that data across systems.&#xA;&#xA;It will enable Anglian Water to manage how shared data is created, integrated, maintained, and used&#xA;throughout the enterprise, by establishing centralised, authoritative, ‘golden’ datasets which are propagated out to all the systems that require such data. A new data integration architecture will control shared access, replication, and flow of data in order to ensure data quality and consistency, either from a single system of record (where master data is consolidated into a single line of business system), or via a ‘hub-and-spoke’ architecture with a dedicated master data hub data store that serves as the single, central point of reference for all satellite operational and reporting applications.&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;Business logic will be developed to match, merge, and link data from multiple sources, and to provide a certain degree of confidence for each match.&#xA;&#xA;For all shared data subject areas, the fundamental questions will need to be addressed:&#xA;•&#x9; What data is required for specific needs, and how do those needs overlap?&#xA;•&#x9; What data is describing the same person, place, or thing?&#xA;•&#x9; Where does that data originate, and how does each instance differ?&#xA;•&#x9; Which instance is of the highest quality?&#xA;•&#x9; How can inconsistencies be reconciled?&#xA;&#xA;Master Data Management is an ongoing, incremental, integration capability, planned and phased. Subject areas should be incorporated in turn, with the most cost effective areas given highest priority, after due consideration of cost v benefit v risk."/>
