<archimate:Capability
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Enterprise Data Architecture Modelling"
    id="id-92c00a82-cafa-4fee-9faf-178fd3bb6978"
    documentation="The enterprise data architecture model is an integrated, multi-layered map of Anglian Water’s data assets, which constitutes an enterprise-level baseline for all ongoing data modelling &amp; design efforts, and a guide for data integration, reuse, and adaptation.&#xA;&#xA;Enterprise Data Architecture Modelling is the capability to develop an integrated, multi-layered map of Anglian Water’s data assets. Many approaches, standards, and methodologies exist (e.g. TOGAF, Zachman) but all have the same objective: to help organise collective thinking about enterprise data architecture, thereby encouraging different people with different objectives and perspectives to integrate their data requirements to meet common business interests.&#xA;&#xA;The output is an ever-increasing collection of models and documentation, at successive levels of appropriate detail:&#xA;&#xA;•&#x9; Enterprise Data Modelling (Data)&#xA;•&#x9; Subject Area Model: essential business entities.&#xA;•&#x9; Conceptual Model: direct relationships between entities.&#xA;•&#x9; Logical Model: essential attributes for each business entity.&#xA;•&#x9; Data Realisation Modelling (Systems)&#xA;•&#x9; How data entities are instantiated in LOB systems.&#xA;•&#x9; Source &amp; Consumer Modelling (People &amp; Processes)&#xA;•&#x9; Data owners &amp; custodians&#xA;•&#x9; Provenance, interaction, propagation, and role (i.e. Master, Copy, etc.)&#xA;•&#x9; Transportation &amp; Transformation Modelling (Integration &amp; Flow)&#xA;•&#x9; End-to-end data flow (data lineage).&#xA;•&#x9; Data transformation.&#xA;&#xA;In Enterprise data architecture, subject areas of data take precedence over systems and operational processes. It defines and standardises terms for the things that are important to the organization, the business entities. It establishes a common business vocabulary of business entities and the data attributes (characteristics) that matter about these entities. Enterprise data architecture defines the semantics of the enterprise. Subject areas will be incorporated in turn, as part of an ongoing, incremental, integration capability, planned and phased, with the most cost effective areas given highest priority, after due consideration of cost v benefit v risk.&#xA;&#xA;The enterprise data architecture model constitutes the baseline for all additional data requirement analysis, and all data modelling and design efforts undertaken at local levels. Conceptual and logical data models for each project should be undertaken with respect to the applicable portions of the enterprise data model, in order to achieve data integration. Virtually every project will benefit from, and affect, the enterprise data model.&#xA;&#xA;Well-managed data modelling and design standards and procedures are the primary enablers of an interconnected analytical data model."/>
