<archimate:Contract
    xmlns:archimate="http://www.archimatetool.com/archimate"
    name="Data Integration Policy"
    id="id-57e3887c-a3de-42d2-b30c-e5284b36c550"
    documentation="Statement&#xA;This policy will be evaluated in detail through the ongoing work of the Enterprise Data Architecture project. &#xA;The high level concepts and definitions are defined below:-&#xA;We maintain data so that it is compatible and comparable and time phased across our organisation to allow us to transfer and process data between systems. &#xA;When specifying new data, or modifying existing data:-&#xA;We re-use of data where it already exists&#xA;We ensure new data is integrated into the existing Enterprise Data Architecture Model.&#xA;This allows us to refer to our Enterprise Data Architecture Model and move, request, and use data no matter where it is physically stored across our systems.&#xA;Additionally, maintaining data in this manner allows us to deliver the commitments in the Information Charter to ensure information can be connected, and viewed from an Enterprise Perspective&#xA;&#xA;Principles&#xA;Data integrations will be documented and governed though a central metadata Management system &#xA;The  Data Owner shall be  responsible for ensuring accurate and upto date  data integration information is maintained.&#xA;The business rules that dictate the minimum  quality of data shall be specified by both the receiving and transmitting partner of a data  integration.&#xA;Each integration partner must describe the purpose that each data entity  performs in the business process and have audited authority granted by the data owner for the data to be used for the specified purpose. Any change of purpose must gain explicit approval  from  the data owner.&#xA;Each integration partner shall  be informed by the data owner if the data entity has become redundant. Each integration partner shall be responsible for changing their business process to reflect the demise of any data entity.&#xA;Each integration partner will publish the interface to  be used to  transfer data entities including the frequency  and duration of refresh. Audited authority granted by the data owner for the data to be used by the interface.&#xA;All integration  interface specifications,  usage and authorisation  status shall be recorded in the metadata management system.&#xA;The consequences of  a data integration failure should be understood in terms of how iit effects the business process and the implementing technologies. and documented.&#xA;Objectives&#xA;Each data integration shall have a specific documented and authorised purpose.&#xA;A detailed specification shall exist for each data integration with enough information to ensure the consequences of removal of the data integration can be understood.&#xA;Strategies&#xA;Actions&#xA;Outcomes&#xA;Performance indicators&#xA;Management planners&#xA;Review program"/>
